Guide to the Joan Jacobs Brumberg papers,1980-2014.
Brumberg, Joan Jacobs papers
- Series IV. Teaching Material
  - "American Families in Historical Perspective" Human Development 359, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "American Families in Historical Perspective"- handouts Human Development 359, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "American Families in Historical Perspective" Human Development 359, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Subject files - Ethnicity Human Development 359 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Subject files - Midwifery Human Development 359 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Subject files - Emotions Human Development 359 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Subject files - Death Human Development 359 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Female Adolescence" Human Development 417, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Subject material Human Development 417 - Oberman (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Subject files - Human Development 417 Adias Barbie (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Subject files Human Development 417 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - "Female Adolescence" Human Development 417, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - "Female Adolescence in Historical Perspective" Human Development 417, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Human Development 417, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - "Archival Research: Exploring the History of Home Economics" Human Development 455, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Archival Research Human Development 455, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Archival Research - Course evaluations Human Development 455 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - "Seminar on Disease in American Culture and Society" Human Development 459, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "Topics in Family Studies and Life Course" readings Human Development 455/ Hist 465, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "Seminar on the History of The Department of Human Development", 2003 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Independent study Women's Studies 499 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "Adolescence in Historical Perspective" Human Development 618 and " History of Human Development" Human Development 685, 1982, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "Social History of American Medicine" Human Development 690, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Flemmie Kittrell- biographical information (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Student paper -"And Then There Were None" (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Student papers concerning women in Cornell, 1980-1996 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Student papers concerning home economics, 1986-1992 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Student papers concerning Martha Van Rensselaer and Flora Rose, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Student papers concerning handicrafts, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Subject files: Anchorage Home for Girls in Elmira, 1900 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Subject files: Barrett Kate Waller - "Some Practical Suggestions of The Conduct of A Rescue Home", 1903 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Subject files: Dolly Booth Letter, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Subject files: Greenhill Pre-marital Exam, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Draft paper by Roland Marchand - "Consumers and Junior Salesmen:Advertising to Children in the United States", 1940 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Subject files: Marion Taylor Diary (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Subject files: Lydia Maria Child (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Subject files: Alice Stone Blackwell (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Subject files: Zelizer (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Subject files: Rosenzweig, Faderman, Palmiers excerpts (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Subject files: Katherine Butler Jones (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Subject files: material culture (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Subject files: puritan evangelical childbearing (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Subject files: anorexia nervosa (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Subject materials: Philip Aries (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Subject material: Isabel Davenport- The Salvaging of the American Girlhood" (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Subject files: Co-education Tyack (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Subject Files: eating disorders, 2004-2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Subject files: sexual harassment in schools, 1990-1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Student papers concerning statutory rape, 1998-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Subject files: girls, boys and emotions and men and romantic love (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Subject files: romance (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Subject files: oral sex (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subject files: "Body" notes (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Subject files: American girls (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subject files: children's savings banks (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Subject files: wet dreams (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Subject files: The Memoir of James Jackson- study guide (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Subject files: ruined/illegitimacy (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Subject files: childrens' rights (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Subject files: orphans (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Subject files: pre-natal bereavement, 1620-1720 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Subject files: dependent children (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Subject files: adoption (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Subject files: child sexual abuse (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Subject files: african-american childrearing (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Subject files: slave children (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Subject files: menstrual biography and menarche (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Subject files: "Early Ideas of Child Psychology" from the Department of Child Development and Human Relationships, 1917-1957 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Subject files: youth in history (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Subject files: early modern family (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Subject files: adolescence - reading notes (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Subject files: families and industrialization (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Subject files and notes: the profession of authorship (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Evangelicalism: "Apostolate of Venus (Womanhood)" by Ann Judson (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Subject files and notes: feminization (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Girls and home economics (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Home economics and professions (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Harvard professor: Carol Gilligan, 1990-1991 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Eating, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Subject files and notes: female lawyers (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Subject files: female lawyers (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Subject files and notes: social work (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Subject files and notes: home economics (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Subject files and notes: women in science (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Markowitz (Film) - notes (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Janet Reno - interview questions, articles (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Subject files and notes: nursing (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Professionalization of nursing in 1890s: Janet James and Isabel Hampton (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Subject files :Florence Nightingale (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Edward Clarke, 1800s (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Subject files and notes: black women in teaching (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Subject files and notes: black women professionals (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Subject files and notes: black settlements (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Mary Richmond - articles (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Articles and notes: Clarke Chambers on social work (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Subject files and notes: volunteerism (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Subject files: higher education (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Subject files: women in science - Alice Hamilton (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Subject files and notes: WWI, depression and WWII (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Subject files and notes: librarianship (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Notes: first generation of women to attend college (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Subject files: black women doctors (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Notes: feminism (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - History of Education Quarterly: Sigawney Drawings (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - "After College What? New Graduates and The Family Claim" by Joyce Antler, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Diary of Fanny Kingman - typed transcript, 1814-1868 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Notes: Charlotte Perkins Gilman (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Issue in Education: Articles by Sari Biklen, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - "Work, Gender and Teaching" by Michael Apple, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - "Female Teacher and Feminist Movement" by Geraldine Clifford, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Subject Files: Origin of 20th Century Gender System (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Notes: Arlie Hoschild's Book "The Second Shift" (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - "Home Economics to Human Ecology" University of Tennessee, 1897-1994 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - "History of the Home Management House" - North Dakota State University, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Women of Japan, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - History 405 assignment based on The Body Project, no date (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Organization of American Historians Distinguished Lecture Series, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Summer college, 2003-2013 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Berkshire Farm Centennial Celebration
  - Book 1986 Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Student papers Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Research Seminar: "Bad Boys" Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Paper: "Saving Truant and Vagrant Boys- The Origin of the Berkshire Industrial Farm 1886-1990" by Joan Brumberg Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Historical Overview: "Berkshire Industrial Farm Center and Services for Youth- Canaan New York 1986" Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Berkshire Industrial Farm Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Records on Frederick Gordon Burnham Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Records on Morristown, New Jersey, European Background Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - "Joan's notes: Berkshire Industrial Farm and donation of collection 1986" Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - "Berkshire Industrial Farm: The Story of Forty Years of Work Among Boys 1886-1926" Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Human Development 455, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Series V. Correspondence, Background Research, Publicity, Book Reviews, Pertaining to the books written by Joan
  - Royalty statements, 1983-1999 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Mission for Life With Editor Colin Jones, 1979-1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mission for Life, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Mission for Life photos (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Fasting Girls contract, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Fasting Girls - paperback rights, 1985-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Fasting Girls - articles and publicity (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Fasting Girls - articles, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Fasting Girls - articles, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Permission letters for visuals, 1987-1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Personal concerning - Fasting Girls, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Concerning book prizes, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Book Review of "Emergence of Anorexia Nervosa as an Emerging Disease", 1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Concerning various contracts, 1988-2004 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Concerning Fasting Girls, 1989-1993 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Contracts, 1990-2000 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Aida Donald, editor Harvard Press, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Publishers, 1990-1992 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Japanese translation of Fasting Girls, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Japanese translation of Fasting Girls, 1993-1994 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Concerning Christina Hoff Sommer and her reading of Fasting Girls, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Chinese film on eating disorders influenced By Joan's Fasting Girls (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Fasting Girls - reviews, 1988-1990 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - American Journal of Psychiatry, 1989-12 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - American Quarterly (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Annals of American Academy, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - The Atlantic, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Behavior Research and Therapy (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Bulletin of The History of Medicine, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Canadian Family Physician, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Contemporary Sociology (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Contemporary Psychology, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Durant's, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - The Feminist Bookstore News, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Food and Foodways, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - The Guardian, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Harpers, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Health, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - International Journal of Eating Disorders, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - ISIS - Journal of History of Science, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Ithaca Journal, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Journal of American History, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - FG Review of Journal of American Dietetic Association, 1989-11 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Journal of Social History (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - London Times - literary supplement, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Medical history, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - MIM Notes, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - New England Journal of Medicine, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - New York History, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - New York Times Book Review, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - The News, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - NRC Dutch, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Pacific Sun, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Joyce Brothers - Palm Beach Post (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Plume Los Angeles Times Book Review, 1989-12 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Psychological Medicine, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Psychology Today (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Rochester Review, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Science (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Science Book and Films (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Science News, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Sci-Tech Book News, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Science History of Medicine (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Village Voice, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Washington Post, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Yale Journal, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Bern, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Harvard University Press, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Concerning various contracts, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Concerning royalties for the Body Project, 1995-1998 (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Permissions for photographs, 1990-1997 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Permissions for photographs, 1992-1996 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Permissions, 1995-1998 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Permissions for photographs - The Body Project, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Concerning the Body Project, 1995-1999 (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Concerning the Body Project, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Japanese translation of The Body Project, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - The Body Project, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Concerning the Body Project publicity (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Reissuing Fasting Girls and permissions, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Concerning video conference on the Body Project, 1999-10 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Kansas Charley, 2003-2004 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - "Kansas Charley: The Boy Who Killed", "Boy Trouble: The True Story of 'Kansas Charley' ", 2000,2002 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Kansas Charley research materials collected (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Cheyenne Daily Sun articles (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Kansas Charley research materials collected (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Kansas Charley research materials collected (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Kansas Charley research materials collected (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Kansas Charley research materials - Lee Malvo Case, 2002-2004 (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Kansas Charley research materials, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Kansas Charley research materials - Abolish The Death Penalty Conference, 2004 (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Kansas Charley research materials - Boys With Guns (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Kansas Charley - notes for book (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Kansas Charley - book visuals (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Kansas Charley - book visuals (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Kansas Charley - book visuals (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Kansas Charley - publicity/ articles, 2003-2004 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Kansas Charley - acknowledgements, 2000-2001 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Kansas Charley - lecture "Under our Wings" - given at conference (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Kansas Charley - permissions and photos, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Kansas Charley - publicity/ articles, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Photo reels (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Kansas Charley: The Story of a 19th Century Boy Murderer", Book 1 (Box 10)
  - Journal with research notes (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Koster Elaine - literary agency, 2003-2006 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Perreault, Russell, Vintage Books and Anchor Books, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Kansas Charley contract, 2008-2012 (Box 16, Folder 48)
- Series VI. Papers, Articles, Book Reviews, Grants by Joan
  - Writers colonies, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Essay: "Thirty Three Things A Girl Should Know" - publication agreement, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Radio notes, 1998-2004 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Notable American Women - Hilde Bruch, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 67)
  - Research on Hilde Bruch, 1987-2000 (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - The Appetite as Voice: A Historical Perspective on Anorexia, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Rethinking the Juvenile Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - "Thin" Melcher Media, 2005-2006 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Brochure: "The Department of Human Development: A Historical Perspective", 2005 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Chronicle of Higher Education "More Than Skin Deep", 2006 (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Article: "Are We Facing Ann Epidemic of Self-Injury?", Chronicle of Higher Education, 2006-12 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Article: "What Was Home Economics?"- New York Archives, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - New York State Encyclopedia- entry on home economics, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Article: Society for Research on Adolescence, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Articles by Joan, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Article: "Girl Talk" - The Australian, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Article: Chronicle on Higher Education, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Exhibit: "A Paradise for Boys and Girls: Children's Camps in Adirondacks", 1998-2004 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Article: Book Review - Hope in a Jar, The Making of America's Beauty Culture by Kathy Peiss, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Paper: "The Me of Me - The Voices of Jewish Girls in Adolescent Diaries; The 1920s and 1950s" by Joan Brumberg, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Articles concerning the donation of John and Abigail Adams letters, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Paper: American Studies Association Nashville Conference, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Paper: "Coming of Age at Kensington, Victoria as an Adolescent Girl"- given to the New York State Association of European Historians, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Notable American Women, Writing Feminist Biography, 1992-10 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Article: "Continuity and Change in the Sympton Choice: Anorexia Nervosa in Historical and Psychological Perspective"- Children in Time and Place, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Paper - "Something Happens to Girls"Part I: Menarche and the Hygienic Imperative, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Paper - "Something Happens to Girls" Menarche as a Historical Problem, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Paper Symposium: "Historical Developmental Psychology" at the International Society for the Study of Behavioral Development, 1991-07 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Article: "From the Psychiatric Syndrome to Communicable Disease- The Case of Anorexia Nervosa" From Framing Disease, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Introduction to the Jungle, 1991-04 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Paper: Harvard Medical School, 1991-02 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Article: "Masculinity and Mumbo Jumbo: 19th Century Fraternalism Revisited" - Reviews in American History, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Articles by Joan, 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Papers: "From Fat Boys to Skinny Girls", 1988 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Article -Book Review - "Brought to Bed: Childbearing in America 1750-1950", "Mothers and Medicine: A Social History of Infant Feeding,1890-1950", 1988 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Papers: Organization of American Histories, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Article - "Zonanas and Girl-less Villages" -Journal of American History, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Paper at Historic Ithaca - "How Victorian was Victorian Family Life?", 1980-09 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Articles by Joan, 1981-1989 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Book Reviews by Brumberg, 1980-1991 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Adirondack Museum correspondence, images and notes, 2003 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Centennial material, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The Body Project", 2005-10-2005-11 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Grant-Mellon, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Grant - NEH: "Our Girls :The Changing Experience of Female Adolescence in America", 1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Grant - New York Council for the Humanities: "Notable American Women: Writing Feminist Biography", 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - College grant proposal, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Grant - President's Council for Cornell Women, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Project proposal - Society for the Humanities "Constructing the self in Female Adolescent Diaries 1830-1990", 1995-1996 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Women's studies at Cornell, no date (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Articles by Joan, no date (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Chapter 1: Girls Will be Girls, no date (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Cutting Loose: The Diary of Yvonne Blue (Skinner), no date (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Coming of Age in Pasadena: The Diary of Lu Henry Hoover, no date (Box 16, Folder 59)
  - Chapter 5: Good Girls, no date (Box 16, Folder 60)
  - Carrie Stoey Diary, no date (Box 16, Folder 61)
  - Diary of Fanny Holmes, no date (Box 16, Folder 62)
  - "Girlculture" in the 1890s: The Diary of Lou Henry, no date (Box 16, Folder 63)
  - "First Daughters" Adolescence in the White House, no date (Box 16, Folder 64)
    Includes slides
  - Teenage Girls in the White House: Chelsea Clinton and the Problem of "First Daughters", no date (Box 16, Folder 65)
  - Horse Crazy: The American Girls Love Affair with Horses, no date (Box 16, Folder 66)
- Series VII. Articles, Book Reviews, Written About Joan and/or her Work
  - Articles from various newspapers and magazines, 1980-2005 (Box 11, Folder 11 to 149)
  - Articles from various newspapers and magazines, 1979-1999 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Articles from various newspapers and magazines, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 3A)
- Series VIII. Conferences, Lecture Series, Workshops Organized by Joan
  - Notable American Women Lecture Series, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 150)
  - Correspondence concerning proposed film "Eating Out" to be produced by The Center for New American Media, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 151)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economics in the 20th Century" conference - final narrative report, correspondence concerning early home economics films, 1993-1995 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Correspondence concerning the book: "Rethinking Home Economies", 1991-1994 (Box 11, Folder 153)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference papers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 154)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference papers, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference papers (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Spencer Foundation - "Rethinking Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 157)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference remarks, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 158)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 2oth Century" conference publicity/program brochure (Box 11, Folder 159)
  - "Rethinking Women and Home Economies in the 20th Century" conference correspondence, conference description, application to the New York Council of the Humanities, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 160)
  - Conference proposal: "Gender and Food", 1989 (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - Women's history workshop, 1986-02 (Box 11, Folder 162)
  - Conference- "Food Practices, Allocation of Time, and Social Rhythms", 1989-06 (Box 11, Folder 163)
  - Publicity for talks and documentary, 1995-2014 (Box 16, Folder 69)
  - Publicity posters, Location: Manuscript Box, 2000-2003
- Series IX. Audio-Visual Material
  - Gannett Lecture Series "Rethinking the Juvenile Death Penalty: The Kansas Charley", 2003-2; V-1083 (Box 12)
  - "Joan Jacobs Brumberg / The Body Project":, Afternoon Report, News channel 8, 1997-09; V-1084 (Box 12)
  - "Joan Jacobs Brumberg / The Body Project":, CNN Saturday Morning, 1997-09; V-1085 (Box 12)